Register of the Henry Cord Meyer papers, 1915-1963
Hoover Institution Archives
Henry Cord Meyer Papers,
1915-1963
69063
Meyer, Henry Cord, 1913-
2 manuscript boxes, 22 phonorecords (1.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, conference papers, notes, speech, memorandum, printed matter, and sound recordings, relating to miscellaneous aspects of twentieth-century European, especially German, history, and to the ideas of the German nationalist writer Paul Rohrbach. Includes sound recordings of World War I songs and of speeches by Winston Churchill, Franklin D. Roosevelt, John F. Kennedy, Joseph Goebbels, Konrad Adenauer and Theodor Heuss.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1969.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Rohrbach, Paul, 1869-1956; Europe; Europe --History --20th century; Germany; Germany --History --20th century; United States --Foreign relations; World War, 1914-1918; Phonorecords; Churchill, Winston, Sir, 1874-1965; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963; Goebbels, Joseph, 1897-1945; Adenauer, Konrad, 1876-1967; Heuss, Theodor, 1884-1963
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1943
  - Two ration books belonging to H. C. Meyer (Box 1)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1942-1947
  - Holborn, Hajo, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Jackh, Ernest, 1942
  - Karpovich, Michael, 1942
  - Rohrbach, Paul, 1947
- WRITINGS, 1942-1950
  - "Rohrbach and His Osteuropa," 1942 (Box 1)
  - "Germans in the Ukraine," 1950. Includes correspondence between Paul Rohrbach and various people, including Fritz August Thiel, Bethmann Hollweg, and Ernst Jackh
- SUBJECT FILE, 1936-1963
  - Croix-de-Feu. Handbills of the French right-wing Croix-de- Feu, attached to a letter by one Max Buhler, relating to the French political scene in 1936 (Box 1)
  - Europe, Eastern. Radio Free Europe reports on various Eastern European countries, 1961-1963
  - Federal Republic of Germany. Government leaflets urging saving, 1963
  - Hitlerjugend. Study and organizational chart, n.d.
  - Luxemburg, Rosa. Article (in Japanese) by Masao Nishikawa, 1960
  - Nuremberg trials. Address by Eduard Wahl, 1947, and notes (of H. C. Meyer?) on the IG Farben trials, 1948
  - Rohrbach, Paul. Letter to the editor of Weltbuhne from Siegfried von Vegesack, relating to Paul Rohrbach
  - Second German-American Conference on Western European Integration and the Future of Eastern Europe, September 8-12, Wiesbaden. Proceedings; remarks of H. C. Meyer; and H. C. Meyer's correspondence relating to the conference
  - United States. World War II pamphlets put out by the America First Committee and by the Committee for Constitutional Government, Inc.
  - Von Wiegand, Karl. Photocopy of a letter of F. W. von Meister to Hugo Eckener, dated March 15, 1946, mentioning Karl von Wiegand and Lady Hay
- PHONORECORDS
  - Berlin Bleibt doch Berlin (1949-1953) (Oversize 1)
  - Das Dritte Reich in Dokumenten (3 phonorecords) (Oversize 2-4)
  - Die Optimistische Illustrierte (Oversize 5)
  - Europe since the War: Ten Years of European Cooperation (Oversize 6)
  - FDR Speaks (2 phonorecords) (Oversize 7-8)
  - Graf Zeppelin - Sein Leben und Werk (2 phonorecords) (Oversize 9-10)
  - "I can hear it now...," 1933-1945, a chronicle of war and the years of crisis, narrated by Edward R. Murrow and Fred W. Friendly (Oversize 11)
  - J.F. Kennedy - Inaugural Address, 1961 (Oversize 12)
  - Joseph Goebbels - Das Dritte Reich und Seine Propaganda (Oversize 13)
  - Kommodchen-Platte, 1961 (Oversize 14)
  - Konrad Adenauer - Aus Meinem Leben, n.d. 2 phonorecords) (Oversize 15-16)
  - "It's a Long Way to Tipperary", original songs of World War I, recorded 1915-1919 (Oversize 17)
  - "Son of Tiperary", original songs of World War I, Vol. II (Oversize 18)
  - The Democratic Party: History, Campaigns, Music, narrated by Henry Fonda (Oversize 19)
  - Theodor Heuss - Der Mensch und Staatsmann Spricht, n.d. (Oversize 20)
  - "Voices toward Peace", n.d., from the Official Archives of the United Nations, narrated by Ralph Bellamy (Oversize 21)
  - Winston Churchill - Addresses, 1940 (Oversize 22)